Now, the thing about creative drama is, and this is where it's going to get a little tricky, depending on where you are and what the rules and regulations of your state and your educational system are.
The educational system today is geared to teaching to the test.
And teachers have a tremendous amount of pressure to get X, Y, Z amount of material learned before this test and on and on the story goes.
Creative drama is not about teaching to the test, it's better.
Because, I guarantee you, if you can take the components that you are teaching, to the test, and turn them into the dramas, the students will learn them better.
The students will be able to retain the material longer than by simply teaching to the test with the direct style of teaching that you're using in your classroom right now.
Students come up to me, ten, fifteen, twenty years later, all the time, and tell me that they still remember this activity, or this activity, or that activity.
How many students come up ten, twenty, thirty years later and talk about the activities, the things that they learned when they were taught to the test?
It's a totally different style of teaching.
So, you can still teach towards the test, in the sense of teaching the same material.
But, I encourage you to turn that material into dramas, take the time to do it, because the students will retain it longer.